Okay, so now I'm
going to show you
how to plan a
case study. So a
case study video is
basically where you show
how you or someone
else achieved an amazing
result that your viewers
want too. So Daniel,
who's a client, made
this video. He made
hundreds of thousands of
dollars. It's amazing. Where
he basically just shows
how he got a
producer full time. This
is the video I've
talked about that changed
my life where I
showed how I monetized
the channel as fast
as I could. This
is my buddy Finzar.
He's doing a case
study on how much
you can make editing.
Now, these two options
are very cinematic and
very heavily produced. I
don't recommend you do
it. I'd recommend you
do more like what
Daniel did, which is
kind of more talking
head style because that
one took me two
months. So it's probably
not obtainable. All right.
So the pros of
these. These things can
build massive credibility fast
because you're literally showing
how you get people
results. They are evergreen
and they can be
bingeable if you do
them right. They're great
for cold to warm
lead nurturing. They can
warm people up fast
and show you're legit.
Now, the cons, I
didn't actually come up
with any. The only
thing I can think
of is, sometimes they're
not great for views,
but that's not really
the purpose. All right.
So who should make
these? Well, I put
novice and pro creators,
so not complete beginners,
because you kind of
need firstly a proven
transformation to shout about.
But also they do
rely quite heavily on
storytelling. So it is
a little trickier to
pull off. If you
are an expert and
you've just got tons
of proof that your
system works, this is
a no brainer for
you. And if you
are a business owner
who's like, I just
need to build trust
in this niche quickly
because it's competitive. And
why would anyone believe
me if I didn't?
Which is how we
should all be thinking.
The type of viewers
who love them, skeptical
buyers who need proof
before buying. This will
get them over the
line. Curious viewers who
love transformation stories. Some
people just love hearing
the inspiration story of
how someone like them
achieved the thing they
want. And then like
business minded viewers looking
for a behind the
scenes process. What that
means is they're kind
of interested in your
business and they're wondering
how you do things
before they buy. And
then warm viewers who
are just looking for
that final excuse to
buy. They've been sitting
on the fence and
they're like, Oh, should
I do it? Or
not? I really, damn
it. I need to
make one of these
because I'll talk myself
into it. Best used
to showcase the power
of your offer or
strategy through storytelling to
highlight real results, even
small ones sometimes just
with a transparent journey
to create an evergreen
asset that drives sales
and builds brand trust.
And then you can
also put these as
part of your email
nurture. So I don't
recommend we ever email
new videos to our
list. Older ones is
fine, but if you
get a high converting
case study, put it
in your email nurture
and then point other
videos at it with
your end screen. Secret
sauce to these. You're
going to want to
talk about every single
thing you did with
your client. That's amazing.
I got results. Focus
on the one clear
transformation or challenge. It
will get too complex.
Otherwise, this isn't about
telling everything. It's given
them just the big
thing. And then you
want to show the
process. So if something
didn't go right, say
that it's okay to
make mistakes. It's human.
It's relatable. It makes
you vulnerable. But honestly,
honesty is appreciated. So
if you're talking about
how you worked with
them and in the
first three months they
went backwards before they
went forwards, that's okay.
And I talk about
that in this course,
right? How does that
make you feel about
me? Like I'm a
bastard? No, you probably
go, Oh, cool. He's
being legit. And then
I would just keep
these simple. We don't
need to go do
cinematics. It's telling me
I've got a spelling
error there. I don't
know why.
So just keep it
simple. It's like value,
right? We don't need
to go and do
these showstoppers like I
used to. Mistake. Turning
it into a very
long, detailed documentary where
you're interviewing your client
about their backstory and
their life and everything
that isn't relevant to
that one big thing
we need to show
off. If you do
it and there's no
real clear takeaway or
lesson, just feels like
a ton of stuff
randomly handed to them.
If it's all logic,
no emotion, right? So
if you run through
this process where you're
like, my step one,
I did this step
two. I did this
step three. I did
this. That's fine. But
if we can set
personal stakes and create
a. Emotion as to
why it was so
critical, you helped this
client get a result.
It's really going to
level up the storytelling.
So if you're interviewing
client and you start
off saying Steve hadn't
landed a single client
for three months, his
wife was pregnant. He'd
lost his job. He
had to go all
in full time, but
nothing he was doing
was working. Six months
later, Steve had a
brand new Ferrari. I'm
going to show you
exactly. So we need
to tie in some
real emotion into this
as to why it.
Matted so much. You
helped. And then if
it's not relatable. So
if you pick a
case study and your
ideal buyer is making,
let's say 10 grand
a month, and you
do a case study
of how you help
Steve go from $250
,000 to a million
a month, your buyer
is going to be
like, well, this ain't
for me. So we
need to tell the
relatable story for our
dream buyers, the strategy.
We need to frame
the whole kind of
case study and the
challenge that you ever
came around this relatable
high stakes problem I
mentioned. And then the
strategy is really, really
using the problem action
outcome framework. So remember
our storytelling, start with
the problem. We then
talk about the actions
we took to overcome
it and then deliver
the final outcome. That
is all our framework
for this video is.
It's pretty simple. So
we have our intro
problem, action outcome. Then
what you do at
the end is deliver
just a logical lesson
where they can do
it for themselves. Hit
them with an end
screen titles. Please don't
use these. They're just
rough ideas for the
sort of titles that
work. But you've seen,
I insert the thing
you did. To prove
it's not luck. They
did something for 30
days. Here's what happened.
Can something process actually
work? How his head
went from X to
Y in seven days
from those stick to
result, which is basically
showing the result you've
used one cognitive dissonance,
which is making them
go, wait, why I
thought that was what
you were supposed to
do. So like saying,
don't buy a house
comparison. So showing a
before and after or
curiosity, just putting something
in your image that
makes them very curious.
So they go, how,
what, why our intro
follows the same process.
We hook them. We
then set up a
problem or a result
or both. We then
set up the information
that's going to follow
in the video, making
sure we dangle in
why we're credible and
matching the viewers expectations.
And then in the
emotion break, let's just
go a bit deeper.
So we start with
what their viewers problem
is, which the viewer
has to have to
then say why they
needed to fix it,
which is going to
raise the stakes. Like
I mentioned earlier, because
their wife was pregnant
and they just lost
their job. Then we
move on to what
were the actions they
took include everything. That
didn't work as well.
And then what was
the outcome now in
the action bit, make
sure you are only
giving the actions that
got them to the
outcome that solved the
problem. If they go
on a side mission
and start doing other
stuff that isn't relevant
to this, the story
is screwed and you're
gone. And then just
improve proof, whatever flipping
possible screenshots, metrics, visuals,
testimonials. At the end
of the day, giving
the action in the
emotion, because basically just
given the steps wrapped
up in a story.
And then afterwards we
move into the logic
brick. Just sum up
the one big lesson
anyone can take from
this at the end.
And then say, look,
here's three steps for
you to do yourself
now, and then keep
putting screenshots of proof
and then hit them
with your end screen.
If you optimize it
for views, push into
a previous version of
this style of video.
If you optimize it
for sales, push into
a high converting video.
If you optimize it
for email, push into
a high converting email.
So with a lot
of the others, I
have an example of
my scripts, which I
break down in these
videos to show you
all these things in
action. I don't have
one for a case
study, which has made
me suddenly realize what
a stupid, stupid man
I've been and that
I should get one
urgently. So I can't
do that in this
case. However, as soon
as I have done
one, it will be
updated. Now, one thing
about producing these is
I would recommend if
you interview a client
for them, don't use
tons of their interview.
People who are not
media trained are often
very boring.
They ramble, they don't
get it. So if
you interview a client,
just tell the story
and then get a
bit of their interview,
which, which backs up
everything you've just said.
So if you turn
around and be like,
okay, the next thing
we did was X
Y and Z Zed.
And that had the
biggest impact. And then
it cuts to John
who's going, I couldn't
believe how powerful it
was when we implemented
this, I lost 3
,000 pounds of weight,
there was a big
guy. All right. So
how to use the
template. So, so for
case studies, set your
goal sales här or
e -mail don't be
greedy. I recommend sales
as a kind of
oratory for this sort
of video. They can
blow up for views,
but sales is going
to be the best.
Then make your thumbnail
and titles. Then work
out your three top
questions the viewers are
going to want answered
based on that packaging.
Then you plan your
emotion brick. So what
was their problem? This
is the template just
to fill out. Why
did they need to
fix it? What actions
did they take, including
things that didn't work?
What was the outcome?
And then include proof.
Just fill that out.
That is a story
template, right? And then
after, plan your logic
brick. What was the
one big lesson? What
are one to three
steps the viewers can
take themselves to get
the same result? Include
proof wherever possible. And
then make sure you've
optimized for one of
your conversion options. So
if you want more
emails, make sure you've
got a lead magnet
tied into the challenge
or the case study,
whatever you want to
call it. Mention it
mid, early, and at
the end, three times.
Link to it in
the description. And then
link to a video
that is highly optimized
for email too in
your end screen. If
optimized for sales, use
your stealth or direct
calls to actions in
your video. Point to
high converting videos. There's
your end screen. Have
your link for your
sales page, top link.
If optimizing for views,
avoid external links. We
don't, YouTube don't like
it when we drive
people away. Link only
to another similar type
of video. Use the
end screen to get
them to binge and
then move on to
writing it. And then
you upload and you
track and you use
the measurement system I
teach you. And you
simply ask, why did
it do well? And
repeat it. Or why
didn't it? And ask
and find that lesson
and just remove the
emotion. Keep making content
and let's get more
data. So we can
optimize the heck out
of this bad boy.